<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arjun's Blog</title><link>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Arjun's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Model Calibration: What, Why, and How?</title><link>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/posts/model_calibration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/posts/model_calibration/</guid><description>Depending upon the nature of the problem and the functioning of the model, the format in which output is provided can differ from model to model. For instance, in a multiclass classification problem, a decision tree provides a label, which is narrowed down going down the tree, where each node reduces the set of possible outcomes to one. On the contrary, the neural networks provide a vector of continuous values, which is calculated by applying non-linear transformations on the input vector.</description></item><item><title>Why evaluating forecasts is hard?</title><link>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/posts/forecasting-brier-score/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/posts/forecasting-brier-score/</guid><description>Judging forecasts can be insanely hard than they are supposed to be. As time passes, the accuracy of a particular forecast seems obvious, but it is hardly so. The crux of the problem is the property that makes the forecasting different from classical predictions, i.e., time. The presence of temporal components makes it difficult to implement the techniques that we would have otherwise used, for instance, randomized control experiments. When it comes to time-series problems, only an omniscient being can replay a point in time multiple times to judge the effectiveness of the forecast.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi! I am Arjun Sehajpal. I ply my trade as a Data Science Associate at ZS, working on Personalization Systems. I have a keen interest in MLOps and Machine Learning System Design and love to work on Time-Series and Causal ML problems. I code mostly in Python, and some Clojure (for personal projects).
When not working, I like to read Philosophy, Fiction, and Poetry. You can find what books I am currently reading here.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/contact/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arjunsehajpal.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Nothing to see here&amp;hellip; Move along!</description></item></channel></rss>